Suppose you're left to decide what degree of polynomial to fit to a data set.
假如你想要确定对于某组数据最合适的多项式次数是几次(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
So that what features to include that gives you a learning algorithm.
怎样选用正确的特征来构造学习算法
Or suppose you'd like to choose the regularization parameter longer for
或者假如你需要正确选择学习算法中的正则化参数lambda
learning algorithm.
How do you do that?
你应该怎样做呢？
This account model selection process.
这些问题我们称之为模型选择问题
Browsers, and in our discussion of how to do this, we'll talk about not just how to
在我们对于这一问题的讨论中,我们还将提到不仅
split your data into the train and test sets, but how to switch data into what we
是把你的数据分为：训练集和测试集，而且是如何将数据分为三个数据组：
discover is called the train,validation, and test sets.
也就是训练集、验证集和测试集
We'll see in this video just what these things are, and
在这节视频中我们将会介绍这些内容的含义
how to use them to do model selection.
以及如何使用它们进行模型选择。
We've already seen a lot of times the problem of overfitting,
在前面的学习中，我们已经多次接触到过拟合现象
in which just because a learning algorithm fits a training set well,
在过拟合的情况中学习算法在适用于训练集时表现非常完美，
that doesn't mean it's a good hypothesis.
但这并不代表此时的假设也很完美
More generally, this is why the training set's error is not a good predictor for
更普遍地说，这也是为什么训练集误差通常不能正确预测出
how well the hypothesis will do on new example.
该假设是否能很好地拟合新样本的原因。
Concretely, if you fit some set of parameters.
具体来讲，如果你把这些参数集
Theta0, theta1, theta2, and so on, to your training set.
比如theta1 theta2等等，调整到非常拟合你的训练集
Then the fact that your hypothesis does well on the training set.
那么结果就是你的假设会在训练集上表现地很好。
Well, this doesn't mean much in terms of predicting how well your hypothesis will
但这并不能确定当你的假设推广到训练集之外的新的样本上时
generalize to new examples not seen in the training set.
预测的结果是怎样的
And a more general principle is that once your
而更为普遍的规律是只要
parameter is what fit to some set of data.
你的参数非常拟合某个数据组。
Maybe the training set,maybe something else.
比如说非常拟合训练集，当然也可以是其他数据集。
Then the error of your hypothesis as measured on that same data set,
那么你的假设对于相同数据组的预测其预测误差
such as the training error,
比如说训练误差，
that's unlikely to be a good estimate of your actual generalization error.
是不能够用来推广到一般情况的，或者说是不能作为实际的泛化误差的。
That is how well the hypothesis will generalize to new examples.
也就是说，不能说明你的假设对于新样本的效果。
Now let's consider the model selection problem.
下面我们来考虑模型选择问题。
Let's say you're trying to choose what degree polynomial to fit to data.
假如说你现在要选择能最好地拟合你数据的多项式次数。
So, should you choose a linear function, a quadratic function, a cubic function?
换句话说 你应该选择一次函数、二次函数还是三次函数呢？
All the way up to a 10th-order polynomial.
等等一直到十次函数
So it's as if there's one extra parameter in this algorithm,
所以似乎在这个算法里应该有这样一个参数，
which I'm going to denote d, which is, what degree of polynomial.
这里我用d来表示你应该选择的多项式次数。
Do you want to pick.
So it's as if, in addition to the theta parameters, it's as if
所以，你还要考虑确定一个参数似乎除了你要确定的参数theta之外你还要考虑确定一个参数
there's one more parameter, d, that you're trying to determine using your data set.
你同样需要用你的数据组来确定这个多项式的次数d。
So, the first option is d equals one, if you fit a linear function.
第一个选择是d=1，也就表示线性(一次)方程
We can choose d equals two, d equals three, all the way up to d equals 10.
我们也可以选择d=2或者3等等，一直到d=10
So, we'd like to fit this extra sort of parameter which I'm denoting by d.
因此 我们想确定这个多出来的参数d最适当的取值
And concretely let's say that you want to choose a model,
具体地说，比如你想要选择一个模型，
that is choose a degree of polynomial, choose one of these 10 models.
那就从这10个模型中选择一个最适当的多项式次数
And fit that model and also get some estimate of how well your
并且用这个模型进行估测
fitted hypothesis was generalize to new examples.
预测你的假设能否很好地推广到新的样本上
Here's one thing you could do.
那么你可以这样做
What you could, first take your first model and minimize the training error.
你可以先选择第一个模型，然后求训练误差的最小值
And this would give you some parameter vector theta.
这样你就会得到一个参数向量 theta
And you could then take your second model,the quadratic function, and
然后你再选择第二个模型，二次函数模型
fit that to your training set and this will give you some other.
进行同样的过程这样你会得到另一个
Parameter vector theta.
参数向量 theta
In order to distinguish between these different parameter vectors, I'm going
为了区别这些不同的参数向量theta，
to use a superscript one superscript two there where theta superscript one
我想用上标(1) 上标(2)来表示，这里的上标(1)表示的是
just means the parameters I get by fitting this model to my training data.
在调整第一个模型使其拟合训练数据时得到的参数theta
And theta superscript two just means the parameters I
同样地 theta上标(2)表示的是
get by fitting this quadratic function to my training data and so on.
二次函数在和训练数据拟合的过程中得到的参数，以此类推
By fitting a cubic model I get parenthesis three up to, well, say theta 10.
在拟合三次函数模型时我又得到一个参数theta(3)等等，直到theta(10)
And one thing we ccould do is that take these parameters and look at test error.
接下来我们要做的是对所有这些模型求出测试集误差
So I can compute on my test set J test of one,
因此 我可以算出Jtest(θ(1))
J test of theta two, and so on.
Jtest(θ(2))，等等
J test of theta three, and so on.
Jtest(θ(3)),以此类推
So I'm going to take each of my hypotheses with the corresponding parameters and
也就是对于每一个模型对应的假设
just measure the performance of on the test set.
都计算出其作用于测试集的表现如何
Now, one thing I could do then is, in order to select one of these models,
接下来为了确定选择哪一个模型最好
I could then see which model has the lowest test set error.
我要做的是
And let's just say for
那么我们假设
this example that I ended up choosing the fifth order polynomial.
对于这一个例子最终选择了五次多项式模型
看看这些模型中哪一个对应的测试集误差最小
So, this seems reasonable so far.
这一过程目前看来还比较合理
But now let's say I want to take my fifth hypothesis, this, this,
那么现在 我确定了我使用我的假设也就是这个五次函数模型
fifth order model, and let's say I want to ask, how well does this model generalize?
这个五次函数模型,现在我想知道这个模型能不能推广到新的样本
One thing I could do is look at how well my fifth order
我们可以观察这个五次多项式假设模型
polynomial hypothesis had done on my test set.
对测试集的拟合情况
But the problem is this will not be a fair estimate of how well my
但这里有一个问题是这样做仍然不能公平地说明
hypothesis generalizes.
我的假设推广到一般时的效果
And the reason is what we've done is we've fit this extra parameter d,
其原因在于我们选择了一个能够最好地拟合测试集的参数d的值
that is this degree of polynomial.
及多项式的度
And what fits that parameter d, using the test set, namely,
即我们选择了一个参数d的值
we chose the value of d that gave us the best possible performance on the test set.
我们选择了一个能够最好地拟合测试集的参数d的值
And so, the performance of my parameter vector theta5, on the test set,
因此 我们的参数向量theta(5)在拟合测试集时的结果
that's likely to be an overly optimistic estimate of generalization error.
也就是对测试样本预测误差时，很可能导致一个比实际泛化误差更完美的预测结果
Right, so, that because I had fit this parameter d to my test set is no longer
对吧？因为我是找了一个最能拟合测试集的参数d
fair to evaluate my hypothesis on this test set, because I fit my parameters
因此我再用测试集来评价我的假设，就显得不公平了因为我已经选了一个能够最拟合测试集的参数
to this test set, I've chose the degree d of polynomial using the test set.
我选择的多项式次数d本身就是按照最拟合测试集来选择的
And so my hypothesis is likely to do better on
因此我的假设很可能很好地
this test set than it would on new examples that it hasn't seen before, and
很可能很好地拟合测试集而且这种拟合的效果很可能会比对那些没见过的新样本拟合得更好
that's which is,which is what I really care about.
而我们其实是更关心对新样本的拟合效果的
So just to reiterate, on the previous slide, we saw that if we fit some set of
所以,再回过头来说在前面的幻灯片中我们看到,如果我们
parameters, you know, say theta0, theta1, and so on, to some training set,
用训练集来拟合参数,theta0 theta1 等等参数时
then the performance of the fitted modelon the training set is not predictive of
那么 拟合后的模型在作用于训练集上的效果,是不能预测出
how well the hypothesis willgeneralize to new examples.
我们将这个假设推广到新样本上时其效果如何的
Is because these parameters were fit to the training set,
这是因为这些参数能够很好地拟合训练集,
so they're likely to do well on the training set,
因此它们很有可能在对训练集的预测中表现地很好,
even if the parameters don't do well on other examples.
但对其他的新样本来说 就不一定那么好了
And, in the procedure I just described on this line, we just did the same thing.
而在刚才这一页幻灯片上我讲到的步骤,实际上是在做相同的工作
And specifically, what we did was,we fit this parameter d to the test set.
具体地说,我们是在对测试集进行拟合
And by having fit the parameter to the test set, this means that
而通过拟合测试集得到的参数
the performance of the hypothesis on that test set may not be a fair estimate of how
其假设对于测试样本的预测效果不能公平地估计出
well the hypothesis is, is likely to do on examples we haven't seen before.
这个假设对于未知的新样本的预测效果如何
To address this problem, in a model selection setting,
为了调整这个评价假设时模型选择的问题,
if we want to evaluate a hypothesis, this is what we usually do instead.
我们通常会采用如下的方法来解决
Given the data set, instead of just splitting into a training test set,
如果我们有这样的数据集,我们不要将其仅仅分为训练集和测试集两部分
what we're going to do is then split it into three pieces.
而是分割为三个部分
And the first piece is going to be called the training set as usual.
第一部分和之前一样,也是训练集
So let me call this first part the training set.
那么我们把第一部分还是称为训练集
And the second piece of this data, I'm going to call the cross validation set.
然后第二部分数据,我们将其称为交叉验证集
[SOUND] Cross validation.
交叉验证
And the cross validation, as CV .
我用CV 来作为交叉验证的缩写
Sometimes it's also called the validation set instead of cross validation set.
有时也把交叉验证直接称为验证集
And then the loss can be to call the usual test set.
然后最后这部分数据我们依然称之为测试集
And the pretty, pretty typical ratio at which to split these things will be
那么最典型的比例是分配三组数据
to send 60% of your data's, your training set,
将整个数据的60%分给训练集
maybe 20% to your cross validation set, and 20% to your test set.
然后20%作为验证集，20%作为测试集
And these numbers can vary a little bit but this integration be pretty typical.
当然这些比值可以稍微进行调整，但这种分法是最典型的比例
And so our training sets will now be only maybe 60% of the data, and our
因此现在我们的训练集就是大约60%的总数据，
cross-validation set, or our validation set, will have some number of examples.
我们的交叉验证集或者叫验证集 就会有某个数量的样本
I'm going to denote that m subscript cv.
我用m下标cv来表示这个数量
So that's the number of cross-validation examples.
因此它表示的是交叉验证样本的总数
Following our early notational convention I'm going to use xi cv comma y i cv,
沿用我们之前使用的标记法则，我们还是使用(x(i)cv, y(i)cv)
to denote the i cross validation example.
来表示交叉验证样本
And finally we also have a test set over here with our
最后，我们同样有一个测试集
m subscript test being the number of test examples.
我们用m下标test来表示测试样本的总数
So, now that we've defined the training validation or
所以 这样我们就定义了训练集或
cross validation and test sets.
交叉验证和以及测试集
We can also define the training error, cross validation error, and test error.
同样地我们可以定义训练误差 交叉验证误差和测试误差
So here's my training error, and
因此训练误差可以这样定义
I'm just writing this as J subscript train of theta.
这里我将训练误差写作J下标train(θ)
This is pretty much the same things.
这和前面完全是一个意思
These are the same thing as the J of theta that I've been writing so
这就是我们通常写的J(θ)
far, this is just a training set error you know, as measuring a training set and then
这就是当你对训练集进行预测时，得到的训练集误差
J subscript cv my cross validation error,this is pretty much what you'd expect,
然后J下标cv表示的是验证集误差，
just like the training error you've set measure it on a cross validation data set,
就像训练集误差一样，只不过是对验证样本进行预测得到的结果而已
and here's my test set error same as before.
另外这是我的测试误差也是一样的
So when faced with a model selection problem like this, what we're going to
因此 在考虑像这样的模型选择问题时
do is, instead of using the test set to select the model, we're instead
我们不再使用测试集来进行模型选择
going to use the validation set, or the cross validation set, to select the model.
取而代之的是我们将使用验证集，也叫交叉验证集来选择模型
Concretely, we're going to first take our first hypothesis, take this first model,
具体来讲，我们首先要选取第一种假设，或者说第一个模型
and say, minimize the cross function, and
使得代价函数取最小值
this would give me some parameter vector theta for the new model.
这样我们可以得到对应一次模型的一个参数向量theta
And, as before, I'm going to put a superscript 1,
然后像之前一样，我们也用上标(1)
just to denote that this is the parameter for the new model.
来表示它是一次模型的参数
We do the same thing for the quadratic model.
然后 我们再对二次函数模型进行同样的步骤
Get some parameter vector theta two.
这样我们又得到一个参数向量theta(2)
Get some para,parameter vector theta three, and so
然后是theta(3)，等等
on, down to theta ten for the polynomial.
一直到多项式次数为10的情况
And what I'm going to do is, instead of testing these hypotheses on the test set,
接下来我的做法，与之前不同的是，我不是使用测试集来测试这些假设的表现如何
I'm instead going to test themon the cross validation set.
而是使用交叉验证集来测试其预测效果
And measure J subscript cv,
因此我要对每一个模型都算出其对应的Jcv
to see how well each of these hypotheses do on my cross validation set.
来观察这些假设模型中，哪一个能最好地对交叉验证集进行预测
And then I'm going to pick the hypothesis with the lowest cross validation error.
我将选择交叉验证误差最小的那一组假设作为我们的模型
So for this example, let's say for the sake of argument,
因此对于这个例子，为了讨论的方便
that it was my 4th order polynomial, that had the lowest cross validation error.
我们假设四次多项式，对应的交叉验证误差最小
So in that case I'm going to pick this fourth order polynomial model.
那么在这种情况下，我就选择四次多项式模型
And finally,what this means is that that parameter d,
作为我们最终的选择。这表示的是参数d
remember d was the degree of polynomial, right?
别忘了参数d指的是多项式次数
So d equals two, d equals three, all the way up to d equals 10.
d等于2 等于3，一直到d等于10
What we've done is we'll fit that parameter d and we'll say d equals four.
我们做的是我们选择了最合适的d=4
And we did so using the cross-validation set.
我们是使用交叉验证集来确定的这个参数
And so this degree of polynomial, so the parameter, is no longer fit to the test
因此，这个参数d，即这个多项式次数，就没有跟测试集拟合过了
set, and so we've not saved away the test set, and we can use the test set to
这样我们就为测试集留出了一条路，现在我们就能使用
measure, or to estimate the generalization error of the model that was selected.
测试集来预测或者估计，通过学习算法得出的模型的泛化误差了
By the of them.
So, that was model selection and how you can take your data,
因此，这是模型选择问题，包括你应该如何将数据
split it into a training, validation, and test set.
包括你应该如何将数据和测试集
And use your cross validation data to select the model and
以及使用你的交叉验证集，来选择最合适的模型，并且
evaluate it on the test set.
使用测试集进行预测
One final note, I should say that in.
最后我要说明的一点是
The machine learning, as of this practice today, there aren't many
在如今的机器学习应用中，很少有人
people that will do that early thing that
I talked about, and said that, you know,
按照我最开始介绍的那个步骤做的，就像我们前面说过的（使用测试集来做模型选择，然后再使用同样的测试集，来测出误差，评价假设的预测效果）
it isn't such a good idea, of selecting your model using this test set.
这实在不是一个好主意，用测试集来选择你的模型
And then using the same test set to report the error as though
然后使用相同的测试集来报告误差
selecting your degree of polynomial on the test set, and then reporting the error on
通过使用用测试集来选择多项式的次数，然后求测试集的预测误差
the test set as though that were a good estimate of generalization error.
尽管这样做的确能得到一个很理想的泛化误差
That sort of practice is unfortunately many, many people do do it.
但很遗憾确实有很多人就是这样做的
If you have a massive, massive test that is maybe not a terrible thing to do,
如果你有一个很大很大的测试集，也许情况稍微好些
but many practitioners,
但大多数的机器学习
most practitioners that machine
learnimg tend to advise against that.
实践者一般还是建议最好不要这样做
And it's considered better practice to have separate train validation and
最好还是分成训练集、验证集和
test sets.
测试集
I just warned you to sometimes people to do, you know, use the same data for
但就像我之前说的，总有很多人使用同一组数据
the purpose of the validation set, and for the purpose of the test set.
既用来做验证集，也同时用来做测试集
You need a training set and a test set, and that's good,
你只需把数据只分成训练集和测试集，因为这能得到很好的效果
that's practice, though you will see some people do it.
所以你会看到很多人是这么做的
But, if possible, I would recommend against doing that yourself.
但我还是建议尽量不要这样做